[Music]
and just like that
the season of our wild sunflowers is
almost over
as they begin to wilt under the quickly
warming sun the lupines bloom
a second wave of wonder
then for a glorious and short period
both exist together
a stunning contrast of purple and yellow
i love this time before the sun becomes
too hot
the world is just full of so much color
the butterflies are awake and so to me
is
the magic
[Music]
as you can see i'm not the only one
enjoying this season my dog iger is just
as enthusiastic as i
many of you were wondering if he lives
outdoors and i will tell you that while
he'd happily spend
all day playing fetch if luke or i had
the arm strength
he enjoys spending most of the day and
night on his dog bed
in fact he refuses to sleep on hardwood
at this point and he is most definitely
[Music]
spoiled
this video will be a little different
this week because i wish to respond to
many questions regarding my cottage
and give an updated tour
[Music]
the last one i did was many months ago
and not very detailed
so i thought i'd give it another try
since last year i have painted more
flowers on the wall holes added
wallpaper and many pieces of furniture
that i love
i'm incredibly grateful to live in an
area that has an excellent selection of
thrift and antique stores
since i prefer to buy things secondhand
i hope this will inspire you to unleash
your full creativity in regards to your
home space
and not be self-conscious about what you
love i get mixed reactions when people
have entered my home
some love it others are not so sure but
the point
is that here i feel safe as if my inner
artist
and dreamer and introvert has their own
space to breathe
since this cottage is only a rental i do
dream of owning my home someday
as you can see i love furniture and
objects that appear to be handcrafted
and high quality
through learning how to sandpaper and
paint and stain i realized that i could
achieve this look on a budget
it took years to find all these objects
some in very surprising places
for example believe it or not i found
this chair on the sidewalk
an artist was moving out of their house
and they didn't want it anymore
it was so unique i simply had to pick it
[Music]
up
this cottage is always in need of some
little fix and it can be hard to come by
plumbers and handymen
so i usually rely on myself or luke or
my mother's innovation to resolve what
needs fixing
another question i've been asked several
times is if the landscape outside of my
cottage has been deforested or changed
by humans
while there are many trees in this area
they grow either in the mountains or on
slopes facing away from the sun
so they can survive the hot summers
where i live is a grassland home to the
native bunchgrass that is crucial for
many types of animals
for example the little quail that you
have seen in my past videos nest in
these grasslands
and sometimes i spy their little eggs on
my walks i think it is easy to forget
that while forests are absolutely
crucial for a healthy world
so are prairies and wetlands to a
variety of creatures
[Music]
i do get a lot of questions about my
wardrobe and so i thought i'd take this
chance to explain that much of my
clothes are gifts are secondhand
and so they're not necessarily from
companies or brands that i would
recommend or purchase from
even though i love to patronize
sustainable brands of buying something
new
i believe the best sustainable habit is
to simply reuse what you already have
that is also how i find pieces that feel
very unique and interesting
by looking at thrift stores and buying
second hand
[Music]
i have a little gas heater for my
cottage that was very finicky last year
but i finally got it replaced
most of the kitchen appliances such as
my stovetop are actually mobile
and i put them away in my cupboards when
i'm not using them
i really like it because it keeps the
kitchen looking very simple and clean
the countertops are also made out of
repurposed wood
and they are one of my favorite parts of
my house
[Music]
the home itself is one room but there is
a small bathroom
this is where mr darcy sleeps in his
little house as he spends most of his
time outdoors in my garden
or visiting with other furry friends
this bathroom has a compost toilet and
it works really well
that along with the ever faulty plumbing
in my kitchen
has made me recognize the true value of
clean water and i like to find ways to
reduce my use
[Music]
as for my shower it is in the building
next to my cottage which you see in the
window
it was built so that someone else could
live here as well
[Music]
i hope you enjoyed this little cottage
tour feel free to ask your questions
below and i will try my best to answer
have a lovely day or night
[Music]
you